Osaka's High School Detective
Hattori Heiji
You rebel ronin who dare defy the Shogunate!
This Shinsengumi, Okita Soji,
will be your opponent.
Come at me.
But I can still go on!
Cut!
Cut! Cut!
You there!
How many times do I have to tell you
until you understand?!
When you're stabbed, die!
Just fall down!
Private Detective - Mori Kogoro
This Mori Kogoro will not fall so easily!
You fool!
You're just a mere extra!
Toyama Kazuha
Heiji's Childhood Friend
Oi! One more time!
One more time, please!
No, no! This is my highlight scene.
Look, it's also written right here.
"Yours is the lead role!"
"Ryoma's Holiday."
That's a common dream to write down.
Fool!
You samurai boy!
What is life without a dream?!
It's still too early to give up.
I'll appeal directly to the Director!
Director! Please give me a chance!
Just a chance.
I'll work with all my might.
"Ran-chan, it's been ages!"
"Truth is, when Heiji was in
the middle of a kendo contest..."
"...he was scouted for
a part in a historical film."
"So we're now in Kyoto shooting it, but..."
"Shin'ichi's Childhood Friend - Mori Ran"
"Why don't you come see the shoot?" Sounds fun!
Shin'ichi, wanna go together?
We can zoom over there by plane.
Watch out there!
I'm not interested in movies.
So he says. You're interested in
Hattori-kun's activities, aren't you?
Fo... fool! No way!
- Kudo-sempai!
What happened on your last case?
That was just an elementary trick to solve.
Um!
- Your signature! Please give us your autograph!
- Please shake my hand!
Another time.
Kyaa! So cool!
Ehh...
Even if you're not interested in movies...
...you are interested in the junior girls.
Wha... what are you saying?
You turn down an invitation from
your childhood friend...
...but you'll be giving those
junior girls your autograph?
Ah, all right already, all right. I'll go.
Excuse me!
It's fine if I go, right?
So I'll go!
"High School Student Detective - Kudo Shin'ichi"
My name is Kudo Shin'ichi.
As a high school student detective,
I was, well, pretty famous.
But one day when I went out for some fun to
an amusement park with my childhood friend Ran...
...I witnessed men in black
doing some suspicious business.
And then those guys made me
drink a poison called ABK4869.
When I woke up...
...my body had shrunken!
If it was known by the "Black Organization"
that Kudo Shin'ichi was still alive...
...harm would come to all those around him.
Calling myself Edogawa Conan, I solved cases
and hunted for information about those guys.
However, this story was from long before
I became Edogawa Conan.
Heiwa Fansubs Presents:
"Conan Special Drama
Kudo Shin'ichi's Kyoto Shinsengumi Murder Case"
"LUNA Airlines/Flight 576"
What is it?
I just heard a scream.
In there...
This is...
He's dead.
Geez, that Shin'ichi.
Where did he go?
- I'm Sato of the MPD.
- I'm Takagi of the same.
No one has touched the body, right?
Well, just a strange young man earlier.
"MPD Investigation Unit One - Takagi Wataru
MPD Investigation Unit One- Sato Miwako"
A strange young man?
- Yes.
- Excuse us.
I'm sorry.
The cause of death was most likely death by
suffocation due to a cervical spinal cord injury.
The weapon was the sharpened point
of a dull-edged tool.
Something like an ice pick.
When a human is struck here,
in the respiratory center of the medulla...
...the respiratory neurons pathways
become impaired...
...and so, unable to breathe,
death comes without a sound.
But then, before the victim was struck,
he was made to inhale chemicals...
...so there's a possibility he had
fallen into a coma first.
But don't worry.
The criminal's still here in
this huge clump of iron.
Oi! Who are you?!
"Yes. This was the first page."
Kudo Shin'ichi.
Detective.
"This was the first case of..."
"...the high school student detective,
Kudo Shin'ichi."
"The Closed-room Murder at 10,000 meters"
The victim is Otaka Kazuhiro, 29.
A professional photographer.
About half a year ago, I read an newspaper
article about him winning the Press Photo Award.
"25th Annual Daily Sales Press Photo Award"
By the way, his passport was
inside his inner vest pocket.
It was important to him,
so that may be why he put it in there.
- Sorry about this, but this is police work!
- Oi, come out of there!
Children should stay out of this!
Ah, since we'd like to take some photos of the
crime scene, could we borrow a camera from you?
I took a photo of it already.
Shin'ichi?
Based upon the condition of postmortem lividity
and given the rigidity of his jaw...
...I believe that roughly 1 to 2 hours
have passed since he died.
- We don't know if that's a fact yet though.
- There are 3 things bothering me.
The 1st point is that while there are bloodstains flown
up against the wall where the corpse was resting...
...there aren't any
clinging to his clothes at all.
The 2nd point is that there is another wound
to the lower left of the mortal wound.
A mark as if he had been scratched
with the edge of something.
The 3rd point is that the insides of his
pants pockets are soaked for some reason.
Even if he had poked his wet hands into them,
they wouldn't have gotten that wet.
Ow!
Put an end to this!
There's no reason to hit me.
I told you this is police work!
Um, in order to check for witnesses
of any suspicious people...
...could you please gather the passengers?
There's no need for that.
There are just 4 suspects.
Wai... wait! Why are you saying such bossy
things for! You're just a high school student!
Why do you say there are only 4 of them?
My seat was in coach at the far back.
People going to the rear restrooms would have had to
pass by me and there were no passengers behind me.
Of those who did go to the restroom
around the estimated time of death...
...aside from the victim,
there were just 4 people.
By checking their faces,
I'd know who they were instantly.
Don't tell me you were up all night?
Well, I guess.
I just couldn't get to sleep that easily.
Fool! Seeing that sleeping face of yours...
...there was no way
I could just calmly go to sleep.
Eh? What did you say?
Ah, nothing.
Well, since you're willing to go that far...
Let's see if you know who those 4 people are.
Sure.
Let's see... The 4 people are...
Ah...
This woman here, the woman next to her...
...the man across from them in the aisle seat...
...and this foreigner in the seat ahead of them.
Otaka-san's seat was...
...right here.
They were all sitting in proximity
to the victim, weren't they?
"Victim"?
What do you mean by that?
Excuse me.
For now, the four of you please
come to rear restrooms.
We'll discuss the circumstances there.
No... Otaka-kun! Otaka-kun!!
No...
It's a lie...
Excuse me, you are?
Ah... Along with these two women,
we're photographers, the same as Otaka.
Say, do I have the right to hear what happened?
Well, since you are concerned with the victim.
All of you were sitting near the victim Otaka-san,
but what is your connection to him?
"Office Worker - Ukai Tsuneo (47)"
I had no relation to him.
Because I'm just an ordinary salaryman
off on a business trip.
"Photographer - Tachikawa Chizuru (29)
Photographer - Saginuma Noboru (30)"
I and Saginuma-kun were traveling
along with Otaka-kun as friends.
Tsugumi here...
"Photographer - Amano Tsugumi (27)"
...was Otaka-kun's girlfriend.
"Freelance Journalist - Edward Crowe (42)"
And the one other person is a foreigner.
Say, Tagaki-kun, how's your English?
Ah, I know a little.
Um, let's see...
(What was your relationship to the victim?)
(It was my first time to see him.
I just came to Japan to buy artwork.)
(Thanks!)
He said he wasn't an acquaintance of Otaka-san's
and only came to Japan to buy artwork.
Thank you!
Ah!
Could it be...
"Once we get them over there..."
"Photographer - Otaka Kazuhiro (29)"
"...these negatives'll sell for a high price..."
"...and we can go on wherever
you like for a vacation!"
"You should be happy having
such a nice boyfriend, oi!"
"Wait Otaka-kun, be quiet."
"Eh?"
"Could you be quiet?"
"Everyone is trying to sleep."
"Ah, my bad."
"I'll be careful next time!"
"Otaka-kun!"
"Behave yourself!"
"Yes, yes. I will."
"Geez, such a scary woman."
"Right, Saginuma?"
"What a boring guy, the rascal."
"Guess I'll take a nap, too."
Maybe he was killed because
of those negatives...
But no negatives were found
on Otaka-san's corpse.
Eh? He should have been keeping them
in his inner vest pocket...
I see. I'm sure the criminal
took it away with them.
First off, would each of you 4 tell me the circumstances
of what happened when you went to the restroom?
When I returned from the restroom...
...Otaka-kun was in his seat.
I remembered feeling a little ill,
so I called for a stewardess.
"Can I help you?"
"I'm sorry. Can you bring me some
medicine to stop motion sickness?"
"Yes. Please wait just a moment."
I also saw the male victim from
the opposite aisle over there.
Why were you in the opposite aisle?
I was restless, so was just wandering around.
"Though I had been sleeping soundly,
because of a noisy passenger, I was woken up."
"It was that man."
It was when Tsugumi-san
was asking for medicine...
...that I saw the male victim.
I went to the restroom right after that.
I was woken up when
the stewardess brought the medicine...
But at that time Otaka-kun
wasn't there any longer.
"Did you take the motion sickness
medicine I gave you?"
"Yeah..."
"That's strange..."
"Saginuma-kun had taken some, too..."
"...but it seems to have been
effective on him, doesn't it?"
"In that case, why don't we switch seats? If you're
next to a window, maybe that'll change your mood."
- "Okay?"
- "Yes."
"Excuse me.
The medicine is for her."
"Ah, here you go."
- "Here."
- "Thank you..."
"Ala. Where's Otaka-kun?"
"Ah... Seems he went somewhere."
"To the restroom? Otaka-kun, too?"
I then went to the restroom.
Then it can be said Otaka-san stood up
from his seat to go to the restroom...
...after Tsugumi-san had asked for the medicine
but before it was brought to her, couldn't it?
Then after that, Chizuru-san you said
you went to the restroom...
I didn't kill him!
Thing is, when I went to the restroom,
Otaka-san was still alive!
"Restroom In Use"
When I asked if he was okay and knocked,
he knocked back!
You knew exactly which restroom
he entered, didn't you?
Eh?
Because the locks to all
the other restrooms were open.
Then, the one remaining person is...
(When were you in the bathroom?)
(I don't remember what time it was.)
He says he doesn't remember
what time it was he went in.
What's the matter?
Well...
...his cologne is so intense.
And now we've heard the stories of
everyone who went to the restroom, but...
Just a moment please.
There was one other person
who rose from their seat.
This person.
Huh?!
I was asleep the entire time!
Your seat was directly behind
the murdered Otaka-san, right?
When Otaka-san was sleeping,
there was no one in that seat.
In other words, you must have
gotten up from your seat!
Stop spouting nonsense!
I wasn't mentioned as one of the 4 people
who got up to go to the restroom! Right?
Eh? Ah, well...
Hey! Be certain!
Thing is...
I have a feeling I was distracted momentarily...
Ehh?!
Well, it was you who...
Anyhow, shouldn't you be hurrying to find
either the negatives or the murder weapon?
That's certainly true.
Well then, all of you come for a physical exam
and a check of your luggage.
And you, too, okay?
Huh? Me, too?
Would that inconvenience you somehow?
- Have you checked the contents of the pen?
- Huh?
It would be possible to hide the deadly weapon
as part of its core section.
Let's see. Next is Tsugumi-san.
Core?
Core... core!
I'll check the core now.
In here we have a passport, a wallet...
Ah look, the core is in good order.
...and a sewing kit with some scissors, but it'd
be impossible to kill someone with these.
Let's see, next is...
...oh, Edward-san.
This is a checkbook from
the American National Bank...
Ah, ask him, ask him...
(What were you going
to use this checkbook for?)
(I brought it to buy pieces
at a Japanese auction.)
(Ah, collecting artwork is a hobby of mine.)
(Unfortunately, it was all junk
and a waste of time.)
He says it was in order to purchase artwork
but that he didn't get to use it.
(I can tell you have a great sense of art...)
(...from that beautiful watch.
Can I take a look?)
(Sure.)
"Though the smell of his cologne
was quite strong around his neck..."
"...I couldn't smell anything from his wrist."
"Didn't he put any on his wrist..."
(Thanks.)
Then, next is...
Saginuma-san, right?
Here you are; go to town.
Ah, um, this, too...
Let's see... You seem to have a lot
of medicine to prevent motion sickness.
I'm weak when it comes to vehicles.
Tsugumi and Chizuro take them too, right?
Yeah.
These are... negatives, aren't they?
What about them?
I'm a photographer,
so of course I'd have negatives!
The person with the woman in these pictures...
It's the American Senator,
Dickson-san, isn't it?
That's fine, isn't it?
Aren't those the same negatives
as Otaka-kun's?
By "the same," do you mean the ones that
were missing from the victim's corpse?
- So if you have those...
- Saginuma-san...
...did you kill Otaka-san
and then steal those negatives?
These are mine!
I took these together with Otaka!
Otaka's photos were far worse than mine,
so I intended to sell mine to a newspaper, too.
You guys heard Otaka talking about that, right?
Well, it wasn't me!
Thing is, if you are suspicious of me,
then bring out the murder weapon!
The criminal should still have
the murder weapon, right?!
But the murder weapon
hasn't been found anywhere yet.
It still remains for us
to find the murder weapon.
But it didn't appear
during the physical checks!
No.
The most important place
has been overlooked.
The most important place?!
The murdered Otaka-san's luggage.
That's all that's left...
Okay...
Ah, which is Otaka-san's luggage?
Is something the matter?
Ah, no...
I just remember he had left his bag
behind at his studio one week ago...
...but it had been cut up by a knife...
So I bought him a new bag for this trip.
I think it's possible he had hidden
the negatives in his previous bag...
...and those cuts may have come from
someone searching for them, right?
Yes...
There doesn't appear to be anything here that
could be used as the murder weapon...
After all, this is just the deduction of a
high-school student affecting to be a detective.
"What is it about this case..."
"If the murder weapon can't be found..."
"...I also won't be able to figure out
who killed Otaka-san..."
"Is someone giving false testimony...?"
Like I thought, you're the criminal, aren't you?
Huh? What are you saying?
At the time this lady was asking
the stewardess for the medicine...
...you weren't in the seat
behind the sleeping Otaka-san.
Just a minute! When the stewardess
brought the medicine I was woken up...
...but Saginuma-kun was sleeping in the seat
behind, right? Otaka-kun was gone, though.
There, see!
I said you were spouting nonsense!
But, even this stewardess saw that, right?
Yes. I don't think he was there...
Oi, what are you guys suggesting?!
Let's hear from the crewmember
who brought the medicine as well.
At the time Tsugumi-san asked for the medicine,
was this person in the seat behind Otaka-san?
I was fast asleep, right? Right!
Wh... whether he was there
or whether he wasn't there...
Otaka-san was there, wasn't he?
That I do remember. He had put on an eye mask
and a blanket and was asleep.
Was there anyone in front of Otaka-san?
As I recall, there wasn't...
I know!
Saginuma's seat was, if I remember...
Right here.
"I knew it!"
"There's no mistake."
"The criminal is that person!"
Geez...
Did you turn up nothing so suddenly?!
"Nothing"? I know who the criminal is.
Eh? No way!?
All that's left is the trick
behind the murder weapon.
Are you okay?
I'm fine, but...
Ah! No, no!
You're wrong!
Hey! Where were you touching me!?
It wasn't on purpose!
Still, they are bigger
than I thought they were.
Ran is a high school student.
Shin'ichi, you PERVERT!
It's not that... Um...
I wanted to ask you this because you've
become a high school student...
Huh?
Wait... What is it...
Ah, hurry and tell me.
I'm embarrassed for even asking it.
That last person; thing is they're almost so.
I see. So that's it...
Huh?! What is it you understand?
I've figured it out at last.
The criminal's trump card for how
they ended the victim's life...
The trick of the murder weapon!
Chizuru-san.
Is it true that there was a
returning knock from the restroom?
What need would there be for me
to lie about that?
Because it seems...
...you went to the restroom
and afterwards, Otaka-san was murdered.
- In other words...
- She didn't lie.
When Chizuru-san knocked...
...there was someone else in the restroom
with the victim's corpse other than the criminal.
Eh?!
Please remember.
There's bloodstains scattered on the wall of the
restroom that got there during the time of the crime.
And yet, on the back of the body which was
leaning against the wall, there was no blood.
That was because the blood from the time of
Otaka-san's murder had dried on the wall...
...and that someone other than
the criminal then moved his body afterwards.
Why was the body moved?
That's because they were
looking for the negatives...
...that Otaka-san should have had on him.
Isn't that right...
...Edward-san?
When you were looking for the negatives,
you also checked his pants pockets.
That was when the cologne on your wrist
got stuck to his pockets.
So in a rush, you washed your hands
and wet a handkerchief.
You then used that to wipe away
the unique smell from the pocket.
The only evidence of that is your wrist...
It doesn't have cologne on it.
Edward-san...
...truth is, you speak Japanese, don't you?
Hurry and speak it for your own sake.
It's as this boy says.
- Eh?! He spoke Japanese!
- He spoke it!
The scandal photos taken of Senator Dickson.
I was asked to purchase the negatives.
When I heard he'd gone to the restroom, I thought
that would be a chance to do a trade with him.
But he was dead.
He was bent over at the waist.
"Restroom In Use"
Though I thought it was wrong of me...
...I searched his body for the negatives.
Then, when I knocked, the one who answered...
"Otaka-kun, are you okay?"
I was surprised at the time.
No matter how much I looked for them,
I couldn't find those negatives.
Edward-san...
...and Chizuru-san, who knocked from outside,
can't be considered as the criminals.
That leaves 2 remaining suspects,
Ukai-san and Tsugumi-san.
Ehh?!
What bothered me was Ukai-san's testimony.
At the time Tsugumi-san
was asking for the medicine...
...he says Saginuma-san wasn't in his seat
behind the victim, Otaka-san.
Well... I wasn't lying!
Even the stewardess saw that!
And I said I WAS asleep!
Neither of you two are lying.
It was the differing testimony
between you two...
...that provided an important clue
to finding the criminal.
Then you know who the criminal is?
Who is it?
The criminal who murdered Otaka-san...
...was...
Tsugumi-san...
...it was you.
Eh?!
You've gotta be joking!
Evidence! Where's your evidence?!
There is proper evidence.
Because Tsugumi-san should still
have the murder weapon on her.
Tsugumi took the physical search too, didn't she?
Even if she was checked...
...the weapon used to murder
Otaka-san wouldn't be considered suspicious.
It would also pass through the metal detector at a
boarding gate and is a thing characteristic of women.
Characteristic of women?
No, no, there couldn't be such
a convenient thing, could there?
There is.
It's Tsugumi-san's...
Ah! I know!
Yes.
The wire from the underwear of
Tsugumi-san's right breast.
- Underwear wire?!
- No, no...
It'd be impossible to kill someone
with something like that!
The wire had been sharpened ahead of time
and then stabbed into the back of his head.
Multiplied using the weight from her entire body,
it would reach the cervical spinal cord.
It's a crime that even a woman could commit.
If the wire that had been used as the murder
weapon was thrown away and discovered...
...the woman who didn't have a wire in her underwear
would have been exposed as the criminal.
If it's that... If Tsugumi takes a body search,
that'd be fine, right?
It's no use, Saginuma-kun...
If they searched me again
they'd find out right away...
You...
Tsugumi...
To start off, Tsugumi-san was in the seat
next to the sleeping Chizuru-san...
...when Otaka-san went to the restroom.
And then, just as he opened the door...
...he was hit with a handkerchief soaked
in chemicals and soon lost consciousness.
Removing the wire from her underwear,
she pierced Otaka-san's cervical spinal cord...
...asphyxiating him to death.
When you were sticking him with the wire...
...that scratch wound on his body was caused by
the wire end that hadn't been sharpened, wasn't it?
To feign that the crime involved the negatives...
...you used the scissors from your
sewing kit to cut up the negatives...
...and then flushed them down the toilet.
And, when Tsugumi-san had returned from
the restroom to her seat...
...using a knit hat and eye mask...
...she disguised Saginuma-san as Otaka-san.
"Ma’am, can I help you?"
"I'm sorry. Can you bring me some
medicine to stop motion sickness?"
"Yes. Please wait just a moment."
That's why Ukai-san could mistake
the disguised Saginuma-san for being Otaka-san.
By doing that, Tsugumi-san created an illusion for
the time when Otaka-san had gone to the restroom.
"Are you okay?"
It was a darkened cabin...
...and all that was sticking out from
the blanket was his nose and up.
It's reasonable to have made such a mistake.
"Ah, the medicine is for her."
The evidence that Tsugumi-san used the trick of
disguising Saginuma-san was a piece of negative...
...that had fallen into the seat next to him.
If a piece had gotten stuck to her clothes
while she was cutting up the negatives...
...it would fall off when she was
setting up the disguise, wouldn't it?
Then, that empty seat that I said I saw...
The seat behind Saginuma-san was free,
so you misunderstood.
What if the seat next to me
hadn't been vacant?!
In that case making such a disguise
would have been impossible!
Tsugumi-san, you had the seat next to him
reserved and didn't cancel it, did you?
By doing so, she would be certain to ensure
a vacant seat next to him.
How could anyone possibly sleep through having
a hat and eye mask put on them and not wake up?
If the drug to prevent motion sickness given to
Saginuma-san by Tsugumi-san was a sleeping pill...
...he wouldn't have awakened easily.
A knit hat like Otaka-san's was
also in Tsugumi-san's luggage...
...so when his shape when sleeping
was recalled, there wouldn't be a problem.
No...
Tsugumi...
Why?
He took the Grand Prize photo
because of a fire...
But it was that photo that triggered
you and him seeing one another...
That's right.
Because of that photo,
I became interested in him.
"25th Annual Daily Sales Press Photo Award"
The first time I saw his photo, my heart quivered.
"The Preciousness of Life" Award
Goes to Otaka Kazuhiro"
The fear and tragedy of a fire...
...as well as the preciousness of life.
He was a person who could
express all that in a photo.
In that case, why then!?
Because of that photo,
my older brother's life was taken away!
Could it be that
Otaka-san himself set that fire...?
Yes...
It had come from his apartment.
The amount of smoke rising up to my brother's
apartment increased by the moment...
I didn't believe it at first.
But, when I asked him about it...
...he bragged about it.
"It was a good moment that
I had been waiting for."
"I made it myself!"
"Onii-chan! Onii-chan!"
There just wasn't any way
I could forgive him.
That's why...
But this is vexing...
I was confident...
...that I had hidden the weapon.
When you reached up for Otaka-san's luggage...
...for some reason you displayed
an unnatural movement.
When I remembered that, I was convinced.
The sharpened point of the wire was touching
your skin, causing you to hesitate unconsciously.
But if that was all...?
It wasn't a big thing.
But what should have been just a casual act was
branded in my memory as an unnatural movement.
It's the small points that can be overlooked...
...that are the most important points of all.
What's this?
Acting all great...
Thing is, touching a person's chest
to find a clue like that...
That's totally sexual harassment!
Oi! What are you saying out of the blue!
Eh?!
I... was sleeping?
"Everyone, we will be landing soon
at Osaka's Itami Airport..."
You're wrong!
You're wrong, I say!
I'm sorry!
"Kyoto
The Film Studio Mystery Case"
Geez. I ended up embarrassed
because of you talking in your sleep.
"Kyoto"
How persistent! I couldn't help it, could I?
Because we took that flight a year ago
and this one had the same feel to it...
...so I unintentionally had a dream about it.
Is this really the right road?
If we keep going just as we are, we'll just arrive at
the Yamano temple, famous for its sakura trees.
This is a shortcut.
"Yamano Temple"
Ala... That's strange.
"Good Luck Bookmark"
Perhaps it's around here...
"Matchmaker"
Ah! Aren't these...
...the Lucky Bookmarks that have been
so fashionable lately?
Lucky Bookmarks?
I don't know all the details...
...but they seem to be pretty popular
on TV and in magazines.
I don't know all the details though.
Ehh... Is that right.
Say. Since we happened across them by chance,
couldn't we take a little look?
- Well, we don't have time... Oi!
- Right! Right!
"Good Luck Bookmark"
Welcome!
Our store's lucky bookmarks brings to both
single people and couples and of course you...
...the nice atmosphere of being a couple and
are an extremely popular matchmaking product.
Eh? Matchmaking?
Yes.
Is that right?
I didn't know anything about that.
How about this sakura-colored bookmark?
They're available for a limited 2 week period
and will only be sold until tomorrow.
Just like with a normal bookmark,
it's also possible to affix your names on them.
Ah...
What should we do?
Fool. There's no way I could buy
matchmaking goods.
Ah, here, here!
I've been looking for these!
Hey Mama, since I want to bring a souvenir
for everyone in my class, please buy me these.
Well, can't be helped.
Say, weren't you guys gonna buy some?
Ah, that's okay.
We'll buy some after you. Right?!
Eh? Yeah..
Then that's fine!
"Merchandise Sold Out"
It's too bad.
That girl bought up all of them.
Some fresh goods will
come again in this evening.
"Welcome - Kyoto Futomaki Film Studio"
(Futomaki = Large Roll Sushi)
It's more incredible than I thought.
They've even reproduced
the old streets of Kyoto.
Maybe so!
What's this? You're still angry?
Not really!
I'm not angry!
Is it this way?
Geez! Shin'ichi!
"Sakuraba, You'll Be Killed"
"Role of Sakamoto Ryoma, Sakuraba Reiichi"
Who was it that sent me such a thing!?
"Role of Maidservant, Sugita Fumiko"
It's just a common harassment letter.
I'm sure it's from a Momoka-chan fan.
It was put in the dressing room.
It's natural to think it was the act
of someone authorized to work here!
Damn!
They just envy my popularity.
Say, stop this!
We're over already!
I'm worried.
Isn't this okay?
Wai... say.
Ryoma has his Oryo, doesn't he?
(Oryo was Sakamoto Ryoma's wife)
I'm Momoka that I'm concerned about!
I...
...just went out with that woman
for publicity sake.
I guess for me...
...it has to be you...
What are you doing?!
"Role of Oryo, Hayashibara Momoka"
I thought you were behaving strangely recently...
...but I guess you're having an affair
with your ex-girlfriend?!
Do you know who
you have to thank for this role?
If you intended to do this movie just for this,
then I'm going to ruin it all!
Resolve yourselves.
Say. Chase after her.
Why?
She might be serious about ruining this film.
I wouldn't want that.
Even if it's just a small role,
I want to finish it properly.
All right.
It'll be okay if I follow her, right?
Sorry for the confusion.
We didn't mean to peep at you or anything.
Where are they shooting the historical movie,
"Ryoma's Holiday" at? We've gotten lost...
- Ah... That would be this way.
- Excuse us.
Ah, you dropped this.
Ah, thank you!
Here.
Ah, thank you very much.
Say! Wasn't she with the Idol
Hayashibara Momoka...
...and the actor Sakuraba Reiichi just now?
"Sakuraba Reiichi"?
Look, that's what they were discussing back then.
Those two have been seeing each other.
It had been in "Friday."
I've discovered how devoted they are!
She's a show biz otaku...
"Role of Nakaoka Shintaro, Iwasaki Ryuji"
(close associate of Sakamoto Ryoma)
Ala, what's the matter, Momoka-chan?
Could it be you quarreled with Sakuraba?
He's been in good riding condition recently.
Disgusting!
Don't speak to me so crudely!
That's dangerous!
Ehh...!
I've never seen a set before.
It's pretty dusty, isn't it?
Shin'ichi!
Hey, are you okay?!
No, no... Sorry, sorry, sorry!
"Ran's Father, Private Detective - Mori Kogoro"
I just raised the sword and it slipped outta my hands.
What are you guys doing here?!
And after we went to a lot of trouble
to come see you, Sir!
Hey, Dad! If you're not really careful,
there'll be a horrible accident!
Sir, you need to hold a sword properly or...
It's Doyle!?
Ran-chan, you came!
Kazuha-chan! It's been forever!
Huh, huh? What's this?
You guys know each other?
We solved a case together once before.
Yeah. I showed Doyle here my
brilliant deductions. Right, Doyle?
- This guy's name is Kudo...
- Do, do...
- I go by the nickname Doyle.
- I'm turning down this role!
What are you saying?!
Don't say that Momoka-chan
won't perform the role of Oryo!
Because!
The acting in the Ryoma role
doesn't match up with mine.
That's why either I go
or you change who's playing Ryoma.
Yes!
For the role of Sakamoto Ryoma,
you must give it to me, Mori Kogoro.
Sir!
Read the atmosphere around you!
That's right!
Fumiko-san could you be my understudy?
You seem to be a great favorite
of Ryoma's as well.
No...
Do you think you're some princess?
I have the leading role!
That leading role was thanks to me, wasn't it?
Yes, yes. This movie, too, is thanks to Momoka-chan's
popularity, so this also concerns the sponsors. Right?
Supporting roles will be silent!
Anyhow, I'm declining the role!
You guys...
At this rate, the schedule'll go all to hell...
Somehow, this is a disturbing
atmosphere, isn't it?
The cause of it is that Idol's selfishness.
Isn't this a lover's quarrel between
Sakuraba-san and her?
I guess those two are seeing each other?
Talk about Sakuraba-san and Momoka-chan
has raised their popularity.
Seems the leading role went to him
because of Momoka-chan's support.
I read in a weekly magazine
that that handsome actor...
...has even insured his own face.
Hmpf! What a narcissist.
- I heard about that, too.
- Me, too.
Sir, what are you doing?
An actor's face is their life.
"Hayashibara Momoka-sama"
I feel sick!
That idiot Sakuraba, angering Momoka like that.
If a popular Idol turns down her role,
I'm the one who loses their job!
I'm sorry!
"Assistant Director:
Tanaka Taiki"
"Movie Director:
Kashimoto Yoshihiro"
" Popular Idol Hayashibara Momoka
and Hot Actor Inside a Car Making Love!"
Yes, then everyone, thank you for waiting.
We will be testing this scene on Stage 44.
Please stand by!
- If you would please.
- If you please.
Sir, do you really intend to go with that look?
Huh? You have a problem with it?
Your mustache, your mustache!
The Shinsengumi wouldn't have had
such mustaches, would they!?
This is my trademark!
No matter what happens, I can't shave it off!
- Fight earnestly, just like we rehearsed.
- Yes!
Then Sakuraba-chan, if you would.
Yes. Are you ready?
- Yes, then Director, if you would please.
- If you would please.
Then this is the main test!
- Main test!
- Then this is the main test!
Okay!
Start!
It's the Shinsengumi! Hurry and flee!
For the sake of official business!
Sakamoto!
Resolve yourself.
You say the dawn of a new Japan
is right before your eyes!
Come.
I, Nakaoka Shintaro, will be your opponent.
Watch out! Watch out you fools!
Watch out, I said!
Those swords aren't real, are they?
No way, they're fakes.
But those sparks...
There's a device in the sword...
...that allows electricity
to flow out as sparks from them.
Just like you, Doyle-kun.
You know a lot, don't you?
You're just like a detective.
I just knew... coincidentally is all.
Nakaoka!
Ryoma!
The rest is up to you...
Sakamoto!
But I can still go on!
I can still go on!
This is bad!
Hattori! Sir! Escape!
My face!
Reiichi! Reiichi!
Reiichi!
- Sir!
- Reiichi!
Hattori!
An ambulance!
Someone please call for an ambulance!
Dad, here?
Heiji...
"Charm"
Hattori's unconscious.
Your father's also refusing visitors.
How could this...
What are you doing here?
You and Reiichi are over, aren't you?
What do you mean by coming to the hospital?!
I was just worried about Sakuraba-kun...
You say such things...
...but truth is, you want to
get back with him, don't you?
Just because your
ex-boyfriend became popular...
How undignified.
That's not...
Don't misunderstand.
A supporting player like you...
...just wouldn't be in synch with him.
Sakuraba-san! After such a large burn,
you should rest for at least a little longer...
You two stop this.
I could hear you from the consultation room.
What's with tone of voice?
I expressly followed you here to the hospital.
Will your injury be okay?
It's not that big a deal...
But it is painful as an actor.
What will happen to your role?
After getting the lead role after so long...
I'll have to talk with the Director...
...and see whether they'll resume with the shoot.
What a fool!
What shoot!?
Look you. If I'm not there,
no one'll care if I had a partner or not!
Thing is, since when are you on such
good terms with unpopular actors?
"Sakuraba, You'll Be Killed"
For now, returning to the village set is fine...
...but the shoot might be canceled, right?
That was such an explosive accident.
It's not limited to being just an accident.
Would you be Kudo Shin'ichi-kun?
Yes. That's right, but...
I'm Inukai of Kyoto's Prefectural police.
"Kyoto Prefectural Police Detective - Inukai Hajime"
Oh, sorry, sorry.
Well...
I've heard rumors about you!
One year ago, you splendidly settled that case
on an airliner, didn't you? That was a big deal.
Ah...
I'd like to have you tell me
that story sometime...
Sure, but before that,
you should have a look at the set.
Oh, oh, I should!
Ah, which way?
This way.
- Are you a Detective?
- Yes.
Um...
I have something to tell you.
Hmm... Sakuraba-san was sent
a threatening letter, huh...
Does Sakuraba-san have any ideas
about who it might be?
He was an action actor who
wasn't popular for a long time...
...but on the set of one of them
he became acquainted with Momoka-chan...
And then she introduced him to
various producers...
...and he started picking up
jobs one after another...
Well, thanks to his lover he became a star...
...so there'd be lots of guys jealous of him,
wouldn't there?
Please stop talking that way.
He's been working hard all this time at it.
Now to have such an injury to his face...
Not to be rude, but what sort of relationship
do you have with Sakuraba-san?
We're just from the same theatrical company.
That's why I became anxious about
that threatening letter...
Is that right?
Please see to it that Sakuraba-kun
doesn't come into any further danger.
Could it be called an attempted murder?
There's neither traces of
a gas leak nor explosive material.
What was it that caused the explosion?
At the time of the explosion, fine particles
of dust were dancing around in this area.
Dust?
Dust wouldn't have anything to do with
an explosion, would it?
A dust explosion.
(Funjin bakuhatsu)
Explosive wind?
(Fujin bakuhatsu)
A DUST explosion.
It uses the characters for "powder" and "dirt,"
so dust. Well in essence, fine powder.
Powder.
Can such an explosion come from powder?
If you apply fire directly to some powder,
it wouldn't burn much...
...but once it comes in contact with
oxygen and floats in the air...
...it's then in a state that is quite flammable.
And, if even one of those particles
comes in contact with fire...
...it spreads quickly around to all the surrounding
powder and explodes with considerable power.
Throwing up a cloud of dust powder
makes it easily combustible...
...and, more particularly,
easy to cause an explosion.
Most likely the criminal...
Knowing that imitation ash
would be dancing around...
...that trick swords would be sparking and that
the fight would be performed around this heath...
...and that ash powder
isn't easily combustible...
Perhaps they replaced the ash with flour powder or
something so it would intentionally burst forth like that.
When you consider the threatening letter...
...the possibility that a criminal was
targeting Sakuraba-san would be high...
Well then, have you made an educated guess
as to who the criminal is?
I can't say anything about that yet,
but when I consider candidates for the criminal...
As long as this movie has Momoka,
we'll still be cooking along on it.
Yes.
Yes, I understand.
Don't worry. Yes.
Idiot Producer.
Oi, where's Momoka?
- Tanaka.
- Yes?
Where's Momoka?
Ah, she returned from the hospital...
...and it seems she's shut herself into
her waiting room ever since.
Again?
Whenever she gets in a foul mood,
she shuts herself in there right away.
Tanaka.
Yes?
Go check on how she's doing.
Understood.
Momoka-chan.
I'd like to talk to you.
Momoka-chan?
You in there?
But, the most suspicious person is...
That would be Momoka-chan, right?
Momoka-chan was quarreling with
Sakuraba-san before the explosion...
...and after that was talking about
turning down the part.
Well then, that decides it!
The criminal...
...is Momoka!
Momoka-san!
Please open the door!
Oi! What's going on?
Ah... I'm Inukai of
the Kyoto Prefectural police.
Well... The actress isn't coming out
of her waiting room.
- This is her waiting room?
- Yes.
Ohh... Well, that's fine.
There's really someone in there?
Yes. Inside that room there's
this bolt mechanism...
...so that means there definitely
has to be someone inside.
This is the only entrance...
That could be a big problem
if she got sick, huh?
Oi! Oi!
I have no choice but to break in...
- Okay! Let's all of us ram it! Yeah, on one!
- Yes.
3, 2, 1... Go!
Is she dead?
Ran, don't look!
Well... There's no doubt but that it's suicide.
The incident...
...took place in a closed room
bolted from the inside.
And if there was some other person in there,
it wouldn't be possible for them to get out...
Suicide...
But, why would Momoka...
The origin was the explosion
that occurred during your rehearsal.
Explosion...?
That explosion and Momoka's suicide...
How are they connected?
- The thing is...
- That explosion was not an accident...
It was a case of attempted murder.
Attempted murder?!
What do you mean?
Ready?
That was a purposefully planned
wind explosion.
"Dust" explosion.
Director...
Those prop swords you used
during that scuffle...
They were prepared so they
would give off sparks, right?
Yes.
In order to give the appearance of power,
productions often use those.
What about it?
The criminal knew about the device in
those swords that causes sparks to appear...
...as well as that ash would be
flying around during the fight...
...so they switched the ash in the hearth with
starch or something that tends to burn easily...
...and intentionally caused that explosion.
Say, that was your deduction, wasn't it?
Yeah. Moreover, he slipped in
a mistake here and there.
And the person who was aiming to take
Sakuraba-san's life in that explosion...
...was Momoka-san, who then committed suicide.
Sakuraba-san.
It was said that you and Momoka-san
were quarreling, right?
That couldn't...
To cause an explosion over a quarrel...
And you were being threatened, right?
How would you know that...?
Umm, well...
I heard from one of your fellow actors...
From inside of Momoka-san's bag...
...it seems the magazine used for
the threatening letter was found.
Here. Look, here.
Anyhow, you were having an affair, weren't you?
She's had a grudge against you
this entire time.
That's defamation of character!
There's no mistake but this was the motive
for Momoka-san causing that explosion.
From among her belongings...
...this was also found.
It still needs to be checked...
...but most likely it's the same powder
that was used in the explosion.
Then I guess...
The explosion was Momoka-chan, huh...
In other words, Momoka-san...
...was targeting Sakuraba-san in the explosion...
...and, getting scared afterwards,
committed suicide...
Right, Kudo-kun?
Eh? Ah...
Hmm, but I feel the rope she was hanging
from was much too close to the entrance...
Well, that was just by chance, wasn't it?
My thought is that...
...it wasn't suicide.
What's that?!
It wasn't suicide?
- In that case...
- Momoka-san was murdered.
And the criminal...
...is most likely inside here.
That room was bolted from the inside
and there were no secret rooms, right?
If she was murdered,
how did the criminal escape?
This isn't some manga or novel...
I'll be solving that trick after this.
No, there isn't any trick!
When you think about the situation...
- ...it was suicide!
- It was murder!
- Suicide.
- Murder!
Suicide! Geez...
I don't know about you being a high school detective
or whatever, but anyhow, you're an amateur.
Hurry back home and sleep...
Hurry! Leave! Leave!
Very well.
I'll go home and sleep.
- Huh?
- Eh?!
Shin'ichi?
Shin'ichi you idiot.
Where have you gone?
Think about the people looking for you...
- Thank you very much.
- Not at all...
What was that about?
What do you mean, "what was that about"?
What were you and Fumiko-san talking about?
What were we talking about...
Bookmarks.
You're buying me one?
Eh?! Ah, well...
Then, I'll take this one!
Since when did you start
selling these sakura bookmarks?
Yes.
These sakura-colored bookmarks are only being sold
for a limited time of 2 weeks up through tomorrow.
Just like with a normal bookmark,
it's also possible to affix your names on them.
Ehh...
Those are nice, too...
Why the sakura-colored ones?
Some reason...
I see...
Shin'ichi!
What happened so suddenly?
I know what the trick was!
Eh? Wai, wait... Wait!
Shin'ichi! Hey!
What about the bookmark!? Hey!
"Popular Idol Hayashibara Momoka
and Hot Actor Inside a Car Making Love!"
I think the shoot will go on for now, but...
With that injury to your face,
you can't have the leading role.
I feel sorry for you.
Well... Just think how lucky you were
not to have died in that explosion.
This is an awful turn of events, isn't it?
Of course it is!
It's your fault that Momoka's dead, after all.
Like I thought, that's how it was done...
And?
What sort of trick was it?
The criminal first brought in a rope they had
secretly made with a hoop in it.
And then...
What?!
Stopping in the middle like that
gives me the creeps!
Shin'ichi!
Dad!?
What do you mean raising your hand
against your own parent!?
You were refusing
to have visitors, weren't you?
Your trademark mustache had gotten burnt,
so you wouldn't go out in public!
Wasn't that why you were crying,
"No visitors!"?
It was!
But...
This is a film studio, isn't it?
You were looking for a mustache?!
Taking an extra, huh?
You should be thinking that that's
better than being injured.
Well, your hair was burned though.
Shut up!
They say an actor's face is their life...
And for me, my mustache
is more important than my life!
An actor's face is their life...
Face?
Geez...
It's Dad's fault this will be
so much trouble to clean up.
Ah. No, no... Don't touch those.
They're scattered around so much.
Ah, not those... Not those either!
Ah, that one's fine though.
That's the one from before.
Eh? From before? Here, here...
Yes, yes...
Here and here...
This might be good, too.
So that's it, huh...
What is it? What's the matter?
I understand everything now.
Because there's just one truth!
Heiji...
Heiji!
No way, right? Heiji!
The truth is...
...I was asked by that high school student
detective to gather all of you together.
Momoka's suicide resolved the case, didn't it?
Well, about that...
Momoka-san didn't commit suicide.
Geez, are you still obstinately saying that?
This was a closed room.
A murder would be impossible, wouldn't it?
I will now elucidate the trick behind that.
First off, the murderer secretly brought in
a rope with a hoop they had made in it...
Telling her that they wanted to discuss
something with her, they entered the room...
...and killed Momoka-san.
And then they tied the rope to a beam
and lifted up her corpse.
The length of the rope at this time is a highlight of
the trick needed to turn this into a closed room.
The length of the rope?
It's a pendulum.
Though the criminal was outside of this room,
by using Momoka-san's body like a pendulum...
...they could put up the bolt from inside.
First off, the criminal removed the middle clasp from
the tabi (split-toe socks) Momoka-san was wearing.
And then they lightly fixed the bolt
to each side of her feet.
They then raised the corpse in that condition
and out through the open door.
When they released their hold,
the corpse reacted by swinging inside.
Taking that opportunity
to close the double doors...
...the heels of the corpse would return and
strike the door exactly due to the pendulum action.
That was how they accomplished a closed room.
There are a lot of marks on
both door and the bolt.
Most likely the criminal
experimented many times over...
...in order to arrange for this trick.
In that case, who is the murderer?
When I considered that, there were two people who
bore a grudge against Sakuraba-san and Momoka-san.
The one with the highest possibility is...
You, Fumiko-san.
Eh?
Fumiko-san?
What was her motive?
Jealousy.
Fumiko-san envied the relationship between
Sakuraba-san and Momoka-san.
Why... would I be jealous of those two...
You're Sakuraba-san's ex-lover, aren't you?
When I came across you two yesterday, I thought
that it wasn't just an ordinary relationship.
To make sure, I confirmed that you were in
the same theatrical company together.
But Sakuraba-kun and I had already broken up.
We didn't have any lingering affections,
so I couldn't be jealous.
Then why...
...are you carrying around
that treasured bookmark?
That's... a matchmaking promotional item's
good luck bookmark, isn't it?
The bookmark you received from Sakuraba-san
does have both of your names on it.
When I picked it up yesterday,
I confirmed that without a doubt.
"Reiichi - Fumiko"
- That was...
- I received this...
...from Sakuraba-kun during the time
we were going together...
...and I just happened to be
holding on to it by chance.
That would be impossible, now wouldn't it?
Why?
These sakura-colored bookmarks
are limited-time goods...
...and were put up for sale just 2 weeks ago.
You were keeping this bookmark...
...because it's important to you.
This is the evidence...
...that you still harbor feelings
for Sakuraba-san.
Fumiko...
Did you really attack me...
...and murder Momoka?
Sakuraba-kun, do you think of me that way?
But...
Fumiko-san.
Since it'd be difficult for you to discuss it here,
I'll hear your full story at the station...
Ahh!
It's certainly true
I wanted both of their deaths.
Detective.
I hated that Sakuraba was
going with that woman.
I and Sakuraba...
...had belonged to the same
theatrical company for over 10 years.
And...
...we dreamed of becoming stars together
that entire time.
I felt it natural that
I would fall in love with him.
But he...
...took up with that woman.
I was betrayed
and only he had his dream granted.
Having a fling with
a famous Idol as a publicity stunt...
When that explosion occurred...
...and I saw Sakuraba getting
his face burned...
...I felt honestly refreshed.
In that case, I guess...
Momoka-san being killed as well...
Dunno.
But if even the police think so, isn't it so?
Fumiko...
Then, Sakuraba-kun.
This time around, it really is farewell.
You have no acting ability,
your face has been injured...
...and I think you'll have
hardships from here on...
But please do the absolute best you can.
Ah, in the end it wasn't
my deduction at all, huh?
Kudo-kun.
There is always just one truth.
What'll happen to Fumiko from here on?
Because she's voluntarily reporting
as a major witness to the end...
...well, a full-fledged investigation
will start now.
"Full-fledged investigation"?
She confessed, didn't she?
Umm, but no physical evidence
has been found yet.
If Fumiko-san left something behind at
the crime scene denoting her as the criminal...
...then she will be confirmed as the criminal.
Shin'ichi, it's about time for
our bullet train.
Yeah. All right.
You're leaving already?
Though I call myself a detective, I'm still
a high school student. I have to go to school.
I was responsible for the deduction.
The rest is police work.
So long.
There!
Up there! Here!
Wait, Kazuha-chan!
Aren't you overdoing it?
It's my long-cherished ambition
to stab a criminal!
There!
Ow, ow, ow!
Dad!
Sir, what are you doing?
In order to get evidence...
...I was secretly using this camera
without telling you!
Damn!
Be at ease.
I struck you with the back of the sword.
Right?
Hattori!
Isn't it about time you accepted it?
It's time to end this play.
The true criminal is you.
It's you.
- Sakuraba Reiichi-san.
You...
Didn't you leave?
If I was around...
...I figured you'd be on your guard about
falsifying evidence, so I put on that act.
This is where movies are filmed.
Even if we're called detectives,
we can put on little acts.
Right, Doyle?
Then...
Making Fumiko the suspicious one...
Of course that was an act.
There was no evidence to prove
you were the criminal...
...so I had to lead you to this point.
Sakuraba-san...
...you were trying to
place the blame on Fumiko-san...
...by leaving one of her belongings
at the scene of the explosion.
Am I wrong?
I was secretly shadowing you...
...with this camera in order
to get ahold of evidence.
Yet even so...
Well, with this it's clear that
Sakuraba-san is the true criminal...
...but why did he cause this incident?
For money.
Sakuraba-san contrived
the dust explosion plot...
...in order to get burns he could then use
to collect a huge insurance payout.
Those rumors about him
insuring his face were true, huh?
When the police checked with
the insurance company to verify it...
...they said he was expected to get an
insurance payoff of 300 million yen. ($3.7 million)
However, you shouldn't have suffered
any burns in that explosion.
The evidence for that is...
This was in the costume room.
This is a shooting prop. Titled "International Law,"
it's a book of international laws from the Edo period.
It was a book Ryoma was always
carrying with him, right?
Between the pages of this book prop...
There was this.
...there was this.
This is a fireproof material
used in fire doors.
Most likely Sakuraba-san put
this book inside his costume...
...where it would protect him against
the heat and shock of the explosion.
Even if Sakuraba-san, in his role as Ryoma,
was found with this book...
...he could say he was creating his role using it
and wouldn't be thought unnatural, right?
Right. And, after the explosion, he got some
charcoal or something from the brazier...
...and used it to make a burn as
inconspicuous as possible to his own face.
What's that!?
Oi, you!
Show us your face!
Such an injury...
That could be easily hidden
with make-up, couldn't it?!
Even a small injury is an injury.
By insisting that
an actor's face is their lives...
...he was just trying to swindle his way
to an insurance payout.
All of your deductions
depend upon your perspective.
Then, Sakuraba-san was behind
Momoka-san's death?
Sakuraba-san's popularity rose
thanks to Momoka-san.
But she almost immediately
turned disagreeable, didn't she?
That Idol was both selfish and deeply jealous.
And so you killed her
and feigned it as a suicide.
Putting the magazine used to make
the threatening letter...
...and the bag of powder used for
the explosion in Momoka-san's bag...
...you intended to place the blame for
the explosion on her.
The bookmark gift you had given Fumiko-san...
...was also a tool you used to attract attention
that you had broken up with her.
Anyhow...
...starting a new office with
the insurance money...
...you thought you could make yourself
a star on your own, right! Right!
Trifling with the hearts of two women!
I will definitely never forgive you for that!
So what's wrong about it?
What's wrong with using women
who I didn't even like?
Not once did ever...
...love either Momoka or Fumiko!
- You bastard! Shape up!
- Sakuraba-san!
Did you...
...ever consider Fumiko-san's feelings at
the time when she confessed to the crime?
When you think of...
...the explanations she could have come up with for
the deduction I'd made, she should have had plenty.
For example, how would it be possible
for a frail woman like her...
...to use her strength and raise a corpse
so it would be seen as a suicide...
...right?
In that case...
Why would Fumiko...
Can't you understand that?
Fumiko-san is still in love with you.
Being self-centered and severely twisted,
that wouldn't concern you, would it?
She...
...was aware of your crime.
But she was never going to say that.
Even though you had broken up...
...she's been dreaming of becoming a star
along with you all this time.
How commendable!
For the sake of the man she loved,
she lied and made herself the criminal...
You just couldn't understand the feelings of
a woman like that, could you!
Fumiko-san...
...for Sakuraba-san's sake...
...she performed a lie as an actress.
But, in her final words...
...I think she was...
...entrusting her true feelings towards you.
"Then, Sakuraba-kun.
This time around, it really is farewell."
"You have no acting ability,
your face has been injured..."
"...and I think you'll have
hardships from here on..."
"But please do the absolute best you can."
Fumiko...
I'm sorry.
For bringing you these painful emotions.
Sakuraba-kun...
Fumiko...
You...!
For putting on that performance...
Forgive me.
Why...
You set a trap for me.
I believed in you...
This isn't the true you.
I'm...
...a beast!
I truly am sorry.
For the sake of exposing the criminal...
...I even asked you to perform
the role of a criminal.
I believed in him.
That he couldn't be a murderer.
But I wasn't sure.
After you had solved
the trick of the closed room...
It was in his attitude.
"Fumiko..."
"Did you really attack me..."
"...and murder Momoka?"
Even if we couldn't get there together...
...at least I wanted to
watch over him from a distance.
I think that even now.
Why would you go that far for him?
Because...
...we were fellows in with the aim of
becoming actors together.
When it's a beautiful woman
such as yourself...
...you can have so many more
wonderful encounters from here on.
This Mori Kogoro guarantees that.
Starting today...
...please start walking towards a new tomorrow.
And, how about me for starters?
- Hey, Dad!
- Sir!
Eh? No...
Just joking. Joking!
Thanks to you, Detective, I can again
walk towards a new life for myself.
Thank you.
For finding the one and only truth.
"Filming Canceled"
Well, thanks to Doyle-kun's "Escape!" you
got away from that explosion safely, didn't you?
That's true.
If it hadn't been for his voice...
...I wouldn't have been able to protect
Ran's father and jump out the back.
But not going to see off the one who
saved your life is really messed up.
It's fine!
Anyhow, Doyle and I'll have
a long fellowship, won't we?
That Kudo guy...
Still pretending to be Doyle
this time around, too.
Next time I'll be the one going to Tokyo.
Your father's really okay now too, isn't he?
"I guess I'm best suited as being
a detective and not an actor"...
...he said, then hurried back home.
When Fumiko-san said, "Detective"...
...it wasn't about Dad, was it?
I really wonder what sort of
thought circuits he has.
- Well, we should be heading back home, too.
- Yeah!
In the end, he didn't buy me one.
Well still, it couldn't be helped.
This is...?
I was out taking a walk this morning.
I just happened down that road by chance.
Let's hurry and get back.
We'll miss that bullet train.
Shin'ichi!
Thank you.
Yo!
"This Drama is Fictional"